Joe Roselli

New York crypta.dev in joe-roselli O bwgh0

Summary _

Senior Software Engineer and Blockchain Developer with 10+ years of experience. Architected systems managing \$2B+ in assets, boosted efficiencies by 86%, and drove \$10M+ in blockchain transactions. Reduced costs by 30-40% and generated 200%+ revenue growth across fintech and blockchain projects. Proficient in 15+ programming languages and frameworks.

Skills _

Languages: Solidity, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, NoSQL, Swift

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Node.js, Express.js, Django, Flask, TensorFlow, PyTorch, jQuery, Sass, TailwindCSS, Next.js

Blockchain & Cryptocurrency: Ethereum, Bitcoin, Solana, Avalanche, Smart Contracts, DApps, Web3.js, Truffle, Brownie, Hardhat, MetaMask, NFTs, DeFi, Tokenization

Data: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server, DynamoDB, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Tableau

Cloud & DevOps: AWS (Lambda, EC2, S3, RDS, CloudFormation, Elastic Beanstalk, Amplify, SOS, SNS), Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, GitLab CI/CD, Terraform

Tools & Methodologies: Git, JIRA, Confluence, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Test-Driven Development (TDD), Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD), Microservices Architecture, RESTful APIs, GraphQL

Concepts: Distributed Systems, Scalability, High Availability, Design Patterns, Algorithms, Large Language Models, Cloud Computing

Experience _

Celsius Network, Senior Software Engineer

- Architected a new CRM system and backend to manage a \$2B loan book, leveraging RPAs, Corezoid, and Mambu composable banking engine
- · Implemented an automated JavaScript margin call engine, boosting department efficiency by 86%
- · Created a Coin Pricing System Oracle in Python using AWS Lambda and achieving 99.96% price stability and accuracy for various cryptocurrencies

Axispoint, Senior Blockchain Developer & Software Engineer

- Designed and implemented on-chain and off-chain blockchain infrastructure for token data track-
- Authored smart contracts for Dynamic NFTs and NFT Marketplace, achieving 99.97% test coverage and 9/10 Hacken security score
- Developed a unique NFT land coordinate generation algorithm using Python, Brownie, AWS Lambda, and Moralis

South State Bank, Back End Developer

- Constructed CRM platform integrating ZenDesk, iTeller dashboards, and RPA systems using Java and PostgreSQL
- Exceeded project time estimates by 18% consistently through efficient development practices
- Optimized check hold decisioning process, increasing efficiency by 79%
- Spearheaded marketing initiatives resulting in 36% increase in credit card sales and 42% growth in net DDA production

Pawleys Island, SC 2018 - 2020

Hoboken, NJ (Remote)

New York, NY (Remote)

2021 - 2023

2020 - present

Education _

BS College of Charleston, Economics

· Distinguished Honors

Drexel University, Computer Engineering BS

· Distinguished Honors

2019 - 2020

2014 - 2017